Quiet.
安oc
Open the door, open the door.
把T打_ 快_T
What?
致
What in the devil?
@到底怎N回事
Can you please stand up and take us to the cash drawer, ma'am?
女士你站起 收y抽显谀难Y?
- I will not. - We ain't asking.
想都e想 - e敬酒不吃
There's no money in the drawers yet.
抽犀F在]有F金
It's in the safe and I ain't got the code.
X都在保U箱Y 我又不知道密a
Prove it.
C明一下
Drawer!
打_抽!
Here.
打_
Open the drawer.
打_抽
- I need the keys. - Keys.
匙o我啊 - 匙
Step back.
往後站
Shit. Damn it!
操他的
Y'all are new at this, I'm guessing.
你是新人? 我猜的
- Where's the money? - I told you, it's in the safe.
X在哪? - f了在保U
- Well, who has the code? - Mr. Clauson.
那l才知道密a? - 克谏先生
He'll be here soon and I suggest you fellers don't be.
他R上到 我建h你so收手
All you're guilty of right now is being stupid.
你@N小嚎谱镄姓媸翘傻了
Just leave and that's all it'll be.
so走 @事也就算了
Tell me I'm stupid again.
你再f一遍我傻看
What time does Mr. Clauson get here? Ma'am, look at me.
克谏什Nr候^? - 你看著我
What time does Mr. Clauson get here, huh?
克谏什Nr候^?
8:30 every morning.
每天上午8c30分
We're walking.
快走
And sit.
坐下
Where do you think you're going? Sit on the floor!
你要去哪?地板上坐好了!
You're stupid.
你才傻呢
This ain't about you, darling.
eo我多事 H鄣
Elsie, you all right?
埃希 你好?
Good morning.
早上好
You didn't have to hit him.
你不用非得揍他的
- Slow down. - I ain't speeding.
慢c_ - 就@速度了
See, little brother, not a worry in the world.
看] 老弟 不用杞人n天
Planning this and doing it is two different things.
]有化快
Maybe we should get there ahead, get up to Olney.
dS我先去W尼
Early bird gets the worm.
早起的B翰庞邢x吃嘛
- Slow down. - I ain't speeding.
慢c - 就@速度了
I found these coins in the barn.
我在Y}找到@些硬
Lord knows how long they've been sitting there.
鬼知道它在那Y多久了
I've been living off an inmate's diet, and had all these coins
我每天衣s食 才了@些硬
sitting right underneath a bunch of feed sacks.
一直在料袋子底下埋著
- This one says 1953. -1953?
@上面印著1953 - 1953?
I wonder if any of these is collector's items.
f不定有收藏r值
You could be sitting on a fortune here.
那你可就坐硪蛔金山了
I hope so.
希望吧
Good morning, folks. Open the drawer!
夥早上好 打_抽
Open the motherfucking drawer!
快他把抽洗蜷_
Ones, fives, 10s, 20s, no hundreds, no bundles.
只要1、5、10、20K 不要一百的 不要成捆的
- You boys robbing the bank? - Shut up.
你y行呢? - ]嘴
Put your hands on the counter. On the counter.
手放上 快放在上
- Yes, sir. - That's it, come on.
是 先生 - @就α 快c
That's crazy. Y'all ain't even Mexicans.
真了 你比墨西哥人不如
Uh-uh, uh-uh. No bundles.
不要成捆的
Just loose cash.
就要散X
Okay-
好的
You ought to be ashamed of yourselves.
你可不害臊
Hands on the counter where I can see them!
手放上 放我能看的地方
Yes, sir.
是 先生
You got a gun on you, old man?
老子身上有]?
You're damn right I got a gun on me.
老子身上就是有 咋地
- Are you gonna get his gun? - Yeah.
快拿下他的啊 - 知道了
Keep up with the circumstances, okay?
控住鲎有胁恍?
- Yeah, I got it. - So are y'all gonna steal my gun, too?
拿到了 - 你打算我的?
I have my own gun.
我自然了
We ain't stealing from you. We're stealing from the bank.
我不是你的 我只y行
Much obliged.
感激不M
Let's go!
撤走!
Sorry about this, folks.
不好意思啦
Dirty, rotten sons of bitches.
z臭不要的王八僮
Fuck you, old man!
操你的老^子!
Go, run, go!
快走 跑啊!
Put the gun on the counter? You trying to get us killed?
你他把放在上?想害死我?
I ain't stealing from some old man.
我不老人家的|西
We're stealing from one place, that's it.
一次只玩一票 H此
You're turning out to be a poor-ass criminal.
你就要成可z巴巴的小罪犯了
Oh, fuck you.
L僮
See what the early bird gets?
早起的小B真的有x吃吧?
Maybe we should hit that branch in Jayton?
]饰可以去茴D分行忠黄?
No, we ain't. We hit those banks
不能 我只鹊你y行
first thing in the fucking morning, when they're empty.
早上第一票真他蠢 空的
- When they're empty, God damn it! - All right.
在]人的r候去 - 真他的
It's the last time I care to be shot at.
@是我最後一次被人射
We got to be smart. We're a ways from being finished.
我得放明c 老干半吊子的事情
Shit, I can do this all week.
我他可以@N^一周
We're gonna.
等著瞧
We're like the Comanches, little brother,
老弟啊 我好比科曼奇人
raiding wherever we please
S心所欲搞突u
with the whole of Texas hunting our shadow.
整德州都抓不住我一根毛
Lord of the Plains.
平原之王
- Hands off. - Fuck off!
手拿下去 - L你蛋
You hear about these bank robberies?
f那些y行的了?
Why are you always dressed like me?
你槭颤N跟我撞衫?
This is our uniform.
@是我的制服
We ain't got no uniform.
我]什N制服
You can wear whatever color shirt you choose.
你可以x自己喜g色的r衫穿
You just keep choosing mine.
你一直W我而已
Ranger regs say white, blue, or tan dress shirts.
巡警手著可以穿白色、{色或者棕色的r衫
Stands to reason every once in a while we're gonna be dressed the same.
基於t 我可以穿同拥囊r衫
Well, you know what they say about imitation, Alberto.
你很明白什N叫做跟屁x 阿托
You wanna hear about these bank robberies,
你到底想摸摸@些y行匪的老底
or you'll just sit there and let Alzheimer's run its course?
是就在@坐著 那些蠢蛋逍b法外?
Where are they at?
他都去^哪?
Texas Midlands--
德州米德my行...
the branch in Archer City and the branch in Olney.
阿爻欠中 和W尼分行
FBI want an assist?
FBI有]有通令?
Midlands ain't got any branches outside Texas.
米德my行在德州以外 ]有分支C
Plus, they're just hitting the drawers for a few thousand.
何r他也只是浊K
FBI don't want it.
FBI才械霉苣
You may get to have some fun
你]蔬能找c纷...
before they send you off to the rocking chair yet.
趁你]退休
I need you sober.
o我清醒c
Who the hell gets drunk off a beer?
l他喝瓶啤酒就醉了?
Place looks like shit.
@破地方真透了
You got anything else you wanna say?
你有什N想f的?
There's not a decent steak
@地方BK像拥呐Ｅ哦]有
in the whole lot of them sorry sons of bitches.
@群]用的|西
Yeah, well, while you were busy in jail,
是啊 你光著蹲子的r候
I was busy looking after Mama,
我忙著照咱老
so you can go fuck yourself.
所以你管去死吧
Was she in that bed awhile?
她在那睡床瘟硕嗑?
Three months.
三月
The end there was pretty rough.
最後A段 人走得也很辛苦
I could've helped out a little if she asked.
要是她跟我_口 我也能退的
I could've fed them skinny cows.
我至少也能喂j那些瘦巴巴的牛
We had nothing to feed them.
我]|西jo它
Well, I could've helped clean up the house a bit.
那我也能打咭幌路块g啊
Never took you for the go-to guy for house cleaning.
]把你成是房g打叩慕KY者
No. Just robbing banks.
不 我只是y行的而已
You know.
是啊
Fuck her.
去她的
She never wanted nothing to do with me anyway.
她才不想跟我有什N瓜葛
She leave a will?
她留z诹?
Yeah.
留了
Am I in it?
包括我?
The will don't matter.
z]什N好看
She left everything to me. By Friday it all goes to my boys.
她把所有的|西都留o了我 星期五生效w我鹤
She didn't mean nothing by it.
她@N做]e的意思
She damn sure meant it.
她^故意的
She always hated me for standing up to him.
她一直很恨我c老爹χ干
We all got punished.
我都得到了土P
You never understood that fighting back makes the beating last longer.
你不懂 χ干造成的痛更持久
No, I understood.
不 我懂
That's why I stopped fighting and shot that son of a bitch.
所以我]再打架 直接懒四狗娘B的
Hey, What's going on?
嘿 怎N回事?
Somebody robbed the bank this morning.
有人今早了y行
Do what?
至耸颤N?
If you see anyone looking a little sideways,
如果你看可疑人物...
Sideways don't wanna meet me.
可疑人物可不想碰我
Find itself on the wrong end of a short rope.
碰我 就是他找K子上吊的r候
Oh, well, that would simplify things for everyone but you.
那真是辛苦你 pp了其他人不少工作
Maybe, if you can find the tree.
也S吧 要上吊先得找涫遣皇
God, I love West Texas.
天 我畚鞯轮
- Ranger. - Hi there.
巡警好 - 你好 (德州警察被Q檠簿)
Wasn't much of a robbery.
劫殿~不多
Got off with just under $7,000.
只了不到7000美元
Took the drawer money, 20s and under, only loose bills.
了里的X 只面值低於20元的X 是散X
- No ink pack? - Nope.
]防I染料? - ]有
- Smart. - That was smart.
明 - 明的作案手法
Can we get a look at the video?
我能看一下O控像?
Let me introduce you to the bank manager, Mr. Clauson.
我o你介By行理吧 克谏先生
This here is Ranger Hamilton.
@位是巡警h密D
- Ranger. - Sir.
巡警好 - 你好
Can we get a look at the surveillance video?
我可以看下O控像?
We got cameras, but they're switching us over to a digital system
我以前有z像^的 最近搞O控底只...
that feeds into the computer.
以便B接到X系y
These new cameras don't hook to our VCRs.
新b的z像^K]有B接到我自己的像O
Call over the Young County Sheriffs.
把你Y的小警L叫
Ask them if they thought to hook their cameras
他有]有把z像^接到...
to some sort of recording device.
任何O渖
- Armed? - Yes, sir. Pistols.
有武器? - 有 手
Oh.
哦
Faces covered?
遮住了?
Ski masks, sweatshirts, baggy pants...
滑雪面具 \由 的子...
- Uh-huh. - Like them thugs in Dallas.
好的 - 就像_拉斯的暴徒
Tweakers, maybe?
吸毒的 也S?
Maybe.
可能吧
A little early in the morning for tweakers.
今天早上有吸毒犯作案
Tweakers don't sleep. They just tweak.
吸毒犯不睡X的 只犯毒a
They rob drug stores and parked cars, not banks.
他只店、泊 不y行
Can I take a look inside?
我能M去看看?
Yes, sir.
好的 L官
Yeah, I'm here, Margaret.
是 我到了 格利特
So they bopped you in the snozzola, huh?
他打了你的鼻子 ?
Yes, sir.
是的
Not very nice.
算好的了
I know their faces was covered, but could you tell their race?
我知道他的遮住了 但你能分辨出N族?
Black, white?
黑人是白人?
Their skin or their souls?
你f的是他的w色是他的心?
Let's leave their souls out of this for now.
我先不他是否黑心
White.
白人
From around here somewhere is my guess,
我猜他就住在附近
you know, from their voices.
姆直嫠的口音砜
Oh?
是?
Young County says same deal with the branch in Olney.
P郡l生同影缸 在W尼分行
Excuse me.
稍等一下
Do they have video?
他有像?
Same deal all the way around.
]有像 c本行似
Doesn't Walmart sell all sorts of electronic equipment?
沃不是有u各N子a品的?
My word. Get your hands off that.
e老是我f的
Well, these boys, they aren't done yet, I'll tell you that.
那些砘r不收手 相信我
- How come? - Well, they're patient.
怎N解? - 他很有耐心
They're just sticking to the drawers, not taking the hundreds.
猿种荒贸涎Y的X 牟荒谜百的X
That's the bank's money. We can trace that.
百元n票是y行的X 能被跟
They're trying to raise a certain amount.
他想一大PX
That's my guess.
@是我的猜想
It's gonna take a few banks to get there.
他要一些X才能蚰枪PX
Your boys know how rich they're gonna be?
你鹤知道他就要l了?
They don't know anything yet.
他什N都不知道呢
You take them to the funeral?
你他去⒓釉岫Y了?
Like I said, they don't know anything.
我f了 他什N都不知道
When's the last time you saw them?
你上回他是什Nr候?
When we all went to the rodeo in Stamford right after you got out.
我一起斯坦福去看了技表演 你正好出z
- That was a year ago. - I talk to them on the phone.
那就是一年前了 - 我F在跟他用M
You talk to them on the phone?
你跟他M?
- You want a little advice? - No. No, I don't.
想我的建h? - 不想
Go see them tomorrow.
明天去看看他
You got any idea how much I owe Debbie in child support?
你知道我欠了黛比多少子女狃BM?
You've got enough in your front pocket to fix that problem right now.
你F在兜Y有足虻腻X
We can't spare it, you know that.
@X不能 你很清楚
Maybe we should hit another branch.
也S我再忠黄狈中
You know, you talk like we ain't gonna get away with this.
知道 你f的好像我[不了@行似的
I've never met nobody who got away with anything, ever.
我就]到^有人可以至诉@行全身而退的
You?
{你?
Then why in the hell did you agree to do it?
那你他槭颤N同意诌@行?
Because you asked, little brother.
因槭悄阋求的 兄弟
I got to shit like an old goat.
我去拉屎 老了不中用
Grab the check, meet me out front.
你去I 在前T等我
Well, if that isn't a hint, I don't know what is.
我f的 算是暗示吧
- You like your steak? - Yes, ma'am.
喜g@牛排? - 是的 女士
Well, you've got a ways to go yet.
你有很L一段路程要走啊
Yeah, you'll be waiting around all day for me to finish this.
是啊 非要等我吃完 你得等一天
I'll be here whether you finish it or not, so...
o你吃不吃完 我都在@Y上班 所以...
you take your time.
你慢用
Sure is quiet in here.
e出
Open the drawer. Fives, 10s, 20s.
打_X 5、10、20K的都o我拿出
Fan them out like a deck of cards.
把X整理好[到桌子上
What do you do?
你是做什N的?
Last job was for a...
上一份工作是在...
natural gas company.
天然夤司
Sounds high-dollar.
起硇剿不e
No, there ain't nothing high-dollar about drilling.
不 井可]那N高的工Y
No one seems to be drilling for gas now, anyway.
F在好像]人天然饩了
They're sure drilling for oil.
都是石油井
I mean, ain't one drill the same as the next?
我是f l知道下一有什Na出?
That's my take on it.
我也@N想
Guess I got to get someone else to believe me.
我X得我得e人相信我的...
Son of a bitch!
婊子B的
We could use a cook.
我需要一N
Just a thought.
小建h而已
Order's up, Jenny Ann.
上菜了 詹妮・安
Bye.
再
Start the car!
快l!
Shit!
操
Fuck! Shit!
操 死
Go, go, go!
快走 快 快!
I bet you don't owe this much in child support.
我敢打你的子女扶BM^Σ灰@多
I must be out of my goddamn mind to ask you for help.
我一定了才找你兔
You wanna get us killed?! Huh?!
你想要害死我?!
That's not a Midlands Branch. That's not part of the plan.
@不是米德m的分行 不在
Now, we got to go back to the ranch and bury the car.
F在我得回去牧雎褴 - 操
- Fuck! - No, we do not.
操! - 不 不需要那N做
We're over halfway to Oklahoma.
我距x俄克拉荷R州只有不到一半路程了
I'm not driving a stolen getaway car to a fucking Indian casino.
我不要_一v偷淼能去印第安
You just put us a goddamn day behind.
你拖累我要晚一天
Well, I got us a day ahead this morning, so I guess we're even.
但@票干的不e 所以F在我扯平了
- You're welcome. - Fuck you.
不用x我 - x你大
Can't you answer your own phone?
你不能自己接?
I'm driving. You're just sitting there twiddling your fat fingers.
我在_ 而你只是坐在那Y掰手指
Ranger Hamilton's phone.
非巡警h密D本人
It's reckless is what it is.
真是太大妄
It's tweakers, I'm telling you.
是吸毒犯 相信我
I don't think these boys is reckless.
我不X得他有那N莽
Damn sure ain't tweakers.
^Σ皇俏毒犯
They know exactly what they're doing.
他十分清楚自己在做什N
I don't know how you're gonna survive without somebody to outsmart.
你是不是一定要@得比e人明 才能活下去?
You need a hobby, and quick.
你得有酆 易W的那N
How about a horse?
TR怎N?
Mary Beth was the rider.
・z是TR的
A horse would only remind me of her.
R只我想起她
You like to fish.
喜g~?
Not enough to do it every goddamn day.
不至於每天都~吧
Yeah, when I retire,
等我退休
I'm gonna move Esme and me down to Galveston.
我要和埃斯米搬到加S斯敦
Buy a fishing boat.
I一lO船
Gonna live on that son of a bitch right at the pier.
住在a^旁 靠他打O生活
Oh, who knows?
哦 l知道呢?
Maybe one of these bank robbers is gonna want a gunfight
f不定那些劫犯
and I can dodge my retirement in a blaze of glory.
那我就可以戴著光s煺峦诵萘
Well, I've seen you shoot.
你的法我可R^
There won't be much glory in it.
和光s@勺职朦c都沾不上
Oh, well, I'm lucky
哦 至少我是挺幸\的
I got a half-breed by my side to avenge me.
上有替我蟪鸬幕煅
If you can stay sober long enough,
希望你保持清醒久一c
knowing how you lnjuns like the bottle.
知道你原住民有多俦中物
What you all doing? You burning this field?
你在致 放火地?
Why in the shit would we do that?
我吃了蔚?
This kicked up on the highway, been chasing us ever since.
@火是公路那淼 追我很久了
Wish we could do something for you.
真希望我能蜕夏愕拿
Ought to just let it turn me to ashes, put me out of my misery.
是它把我成灰斫饷我吧
Cut that fence.
剪了那h笆
21st century, I'm racing a fire to the river with a herd of cattle.
都21世o了 我在s牲口c火谋荣著^河
And I wonder why my kids won't do this shit for a living.
算知道我家孩子槭颤N不想诌@行了
Move 'em out. Come on.
走起 快走
Go, go! go-
快 快 快
You wanna call it in?
你要求支援?
Oh, it's gonna burn out when it hits the Brazos.
等它到布拉索斯河 自己就绲
No one to call around here, anyway.
再f@荒山野X的哪赫业玫绞颤N支援
No, these boys is on their own.
@些小子只能靠自己了
I still don't see the problem, Toby.
我是不明白有什N} 托比
You still don't...
你是...
Well, the problem is, thanks to you,
}在於 拜你所n
we have to spend tomorrow morning getting another car,
我必挨到明早 再去搞v
so we'll have to hit two banks on Wednesday.
所以L三得杉毅y行
We already done three today.
我今天已了三家了
Stop worrying.
e心了
Whose land is this?
@是l的地P?
Jeremy Chalker.
苋鹈住炭
He lets me stay here in exchange for shooting coyotes.
他我待在@Y l件是退打土狼
Cold beer in the fridge.
冰箱Y有冰啤酒
You stole my hat.
你偷了我的帽子
I borrowed it.
是借
What the fuck you do to it?
你他λ做了什N?
- What's this? - My livelihood.
@是什N? - 我的一家一
We don't need all this.
我用不著全上
Can't keep the guns in the trailer days on end.
不能天天把放在房上啊
That's not coming with us in the bank.
@然也不能нMy行
Just spoke to the teller.
和出{T吧
She's a little shook up.
她有c牧
Perp took her driver's license,
可能她的{照被拿走了
threatened her family if she talked to us.
用以威{家人 使她]嘴
Mind if I ask you your name, young lady?
你叫什N名字 @位年p的女士?
Natalie Martinez.
娜塔莉・R丁人
Well, Natalie, I want you to know
好的 娜塔莉 我希望你知道
we're gonna have some officers watching your house extra careful
在我抓到@些歹徒之前...
till we catch these buggers.
派警T守在你家附近
You have my word on that.
我向你保C
There's more than one?
不止一歹徒?
Only one man robbed the bank?
y行的只有一?
- Yeah. - What'd he look like?
是的 - 他L什N?
He was dressed like a cowpoke except for the ski mask.
他穿的像牛仔 但戴了滑雪面具
I think he ran to a car that was parked out front of the diner.
他好像逃M了停在餐^外面的Y
You saw the car?
你看到有?
It was green.
G色的
- How old? - I don't know cars, mister.
壮尚碌幼? - 我不是很懂 先生
Well, was it a nice car, an okay car,
好吧 那看起硎禽v好 是一般的
or a real piece of shit?
或者是超破?
It was a real piece of shit.
超破
All right. Now, we're getting somewhere.
好的 F在我有c索了
Oh, that looks like a man who could foreclose on a house.
那砹艘有XI屋的男人
Excuse me, Natalie.
我先走一步了 {塔利
Excuse me, Mr. Banker.
打_一下 行L先生
Natalie, I'm gonna have the officer stay with you till your father arrives.
{塔利 在你父H抵_前 我派警Tc你一起
- All right? - Okay.
好? - 好的
Didn't happen to have your surveillance cameras on this morning, did you?
你今早有]有碰巧到O控 有?
Of course.
然
Oh, so you have the robbery on video.
所以你拍到@起劫了
Of course we do.
@是然
What kind of bank would we be if we didn't have video surveillance?
如果]有O控 我算是y行?
Oh, you'd be a Texas Midlands Bank.
@然德州米m德y行例外
All right, we've got video.
好的 那我有像了
Care to give it a watch while I wander over to the burger joint?
我去街角h堡店t解下情r 拜仔看下像?
Would you order me something while you're there?
能臀翼便c吃的?
- I'm starving. - I doubt they serve pemmican.
我好I - 我岩伤家有]有乾肉u（北美印地安人的一N主要食品）
You know I'm part Mexican, too.
你知道我也算墨西哥人
Yeah, well, I'm gonna get to that
好吧 如果哪天我玩蛄擞〉诎踩说亩巫
when I'm through with the Indian insults,
我住玩墨西哥人的段子
but it's gonna be a while.
不^那是很久以後的事了
You rangers are an odd bunch.
你@些巡警都@N怪?
No, just him.
不 他是例外
Let's take a look at that video.
我看看像吧
Yeah, it's right back here.
好 就在@後面
Howdy.
您好
Ma'am.
女士
Guess you know about the goings-on at the bank.
我猜你知道y行l生的事吧
I did notice.
我]注意
Any out-of-towners come through today?
今天有外地人磉^?
Jenny Ann waited on a couple of boys, ain't from here.
詹妮・安在@服者^男的 不是本地人
Oh?
哦?
I'll go get her.
我去叫她
Appreciate that.
非常感x
Boys.
朋友
Y'all been here for a while?
你在@坐了挺久了吧?
Well, long enough to watch a bank getting robbed
挺久了 久到目袅四...
that's been robbing me for 30 years.
我30年X的y行被的全^程
Oh, you say you've seen them?
所以你看他了?
I'm pretty sure they were sitting right over there having lunch.
我可以十分_定f 他是坐在那吃的午
One of them was tall.
其中一高
The other one was short.
另一矮
They's both lean like cowboys.
都和牛仔一邮
Looked like brothers if you ask me.
要我f的 看起硐袷切值
You the Texas Ranger?
你是德州巡警?
Yes, ma'am.
是的 女士
Tell me about those handsome young strangers that you waited on.
和我你服盏哪年p英俊的陌生人吧
Who said handsome?
lf英俊了?
I did.
相信我
Based on the fact that you didn't meet me in the parking lot,
b於你]有n到停鱿蛭...
hollering about the two out-of-towners
抱怨有外地人...
eating here right before a bank robbery.
y行之前在@吃的事
Well, they didn't mention they was robbing the bank.
他又]fy行
They paid cash?
他付的F金?
That a crime now?
那也算犯罪?
How much did they leave?
他o了多少小M?
How much?
多少?
$200.
200美元
And they left it before the bank was robbed, so...
他在y行前就o了 所以...
Uh, before this bank was robbed.
在y行前
I'm gonna need to see them bills.
我要看看他o的X
- Ma'am. - Mm-mm.
女士 - 不行
Ma'am, them bills is evidence.
女士 他的X是C之一
Mm-mm, it's evidence if they're the bank robbers.
只有_定他是y行劫犯才算C
Till then, it's my tip.
在那之前 @是我的小M
And half my mortgage.
@可是我房子月供的一半
So, you go out there and you get a warrant,
所以麻┠闳ツ沁拿到C之後
and you come after the money
再磉@Y要走@P
that I will be using to keep a roof over my daughter's head.
@PX用肀ＷC我女翰睡大街
One man hit the bank, just like she said.
有男人了y行 正如她所f的
- Yeah. - Checkered button-down shirt,
是的 格子r衫 扣I子
jeans, ski mask.
牛仔 滑雪面具
- That's all the video will tell us. - Yep. Yep.
像上都有
Checkered shirt. That is him.
花格r衫 就是他了
They were sitting right over there. Tipped her $200.
他在那坐^ o了她200美元小M
Go wrestle a description
去和N房Y的...
from that big sassy girl in the kitchen.
大野U女友vv道理吧
You didn't get it yourself?
你自己]搞定?
Oh, and get that tip from her. We're gonna check them bills.
有 把她那P小M拿到手 我得z查他的X
Good luck.
祝你好\
Yeah, I'd expect some resistance.
是啊 我遭到了B抵抗
Oh, and, Alberto,
哦 有 阿托
call that motel on 287, get us a room.
打o287的旅^ o咱留g房
We're gonna stay the night?
我要在@^夜?
Well, this is where the action is.
@可是犯罪F
Seems foolish.
太蠢了
What's that?
怎Nv?
The days of robbing banks and trying to live to spend the money...
靠打劫y行 然後好命花X的好日子...
they're long gone.
已一去不头盗
Long gone for sure.
^κ顷年fv了
What does Justin want to do when he's grown?
Z斯汀L大後想做什N?
Right now he's dreaming of slinging a football for A&M.
他F在粝榈轮A＆M大W打橄烨
He's a lot like you.
他和你太像了
- I bet that puckers your red eye. - More than you know.
我敢肯定@你很眼w - 超乎你的想像
39 years of life, 10 in jail.
我活了39年 10年在OzY
If he turn left where I turned right, he'll be okay.
如果他是c我背道而Y 倒是正_的方向
Let the world call me a fool
*世人皆以吾愚 Let the world call me a fool*
Things are right with me and you
*唯君平安 Things are right with me and you*
You want anything?
你想要什N?
Dr Pepper, Winston Lights.
胡椒博士（一N焦糖碳酸料） zDLights香
It's okay. Come on.
]PS的
What?
稚?
What, bitch?
看什N看 v人?
You looking for trouble, motherfucker?
你想找死 混蛋?
You came to the right place.
那你Φ胤搅
Boy, you'd think there were 10 of me.
孩子 你不妨假想@Y有十我
Oh, yeah?
哦 是?
Not so fucking tough now, are you, bitch?
你他F在敢@N硬 v人?
Hey, man, he had it coming.
夥 他自找的
He had it coming.
他活 他活
You got some spunk left in you.
你存了c血性
Oh, you remembered the gun.
居然得有
You're getting to be old hat at this.
你已老的_始忘事了
Asshole could've killed you.
那混蛋可能⒘四愕
Ah, not the way it would have gone, little brother.
啊 那可未必 老弟
10 of me, I told you!
十我 我警告^你!
Are you trying to make me mad?
你是想我生?
I said Dr Pepper. This is Mr. Pibb.
我f了要胡椒博士 你I的是皮伯先生(可口可樊a品)
That's all they had.
他只u@
Only assholes drink Mr. Pibb.
傻子才喝皮伯先生
Drink up.
喝你的吧
Hello.
你好
No!
不!
Now we're talking.
我不妨...
The women in this place.
@地方的女人
What the hell you talking about?
你他在f什N?
We should get another shot. They'll be pretty soon enough.
我再硪槐 她^就漂亮了
Bartender, whiskeys if you please.
酒保 再o我肀威士忌
Coming UP-
砹
To your boys.
敬你的孩子
Let's go change that money.
我去Q些Ia
Sorry. I just sold my car.
Σ黄 我u了
This is how the fella paid me.
那夥就是@No我X的
We take it any way you bring it, mister.
不管怎NУ腻X 我都收 先生
Wanna play some poker?
想玩牌?
I don't gamble.
我不博
You can't lose at poker, not even you.
玩牌不的 B你都不
I'm gonna watch the Aggie game and have a beer.
我要喝c酒 去看Aggie(rW院的eQ)比
All right, suit yourself.
你S意
Come on, now.
差不多就行了
Suck a D.
我擦
Don't lose it all.
e都光了
Eat my A!
舔我菊花吧
Fucking asshole.
死的混蛋
That's, uh-- that's quite a stack.
@Y好多Ia啊
Check?
^牌?
Don't chase me, chief.
e追我的牌 酋L
You Comanche?
你是科曼奇族人?
Lords of the Plains.
平原之王
Lords of Nothing now.
F在是 o地之王
I call.
我跟
Show your cards, gentlemen.
亮牌 先生
Do you know what Comanche means?
你知道科曼奇是什N意思?
It means enemies forever.
它意味著永h的橙
Enemies with who?
l是你的橙?
Everyone.
每人
You know what that makes me?
你知道那使我成什N?
An enemy.
橙
No.
不
It makes me a Comanche.
我成科曼奇人
Does he look like you?
他和你L得像?
I see his mom in him.
我在他身上能看他的影子
Everybody else sees me.
e人f像我
I don't know.
我也不知道
You staying in the hotel?
你有住旅^?
Yeah.
有
Take me to your room.
我去你的房g
Thank you. Just, uh...
xx你 只是 呃...
There's no shame in needing the touch of a woman.
需要女人的嵛K不可u
You need it.
你需要
I know you do.
我知道你很需要
Just let me touch you.
我崦你吧
Trying to work my little brother?
你是在勾引我弟弟?
- No, I wasn't doing anything, but I... - Tanner, she didn't do nothin'.
不 我什N都]做 我… - 坦{ 她什N也]做
- She didn't do nothin'. - But, but, but, but, but...
她什N都]做 - 但是 但是 但是 但是 但是
You saw there was a stack of chips here.
你看到@有一大摞Ia
- Don't. - Easy mark?
不要 - 快X是吧?
- Uh... no. - What were you gonna do?
呃 不是 - 那你想怎Nk?
Bring him up to his room, call your pimp,
把他У剿的房g 去喊皮l
-roll him, drug him, what? - No. I...
翻倒他 o他下 是不是? - 不  我...
- What were you gonna do? - Tanner, no.
你T用的伎z 是不是? - 坦{ e@
Mind if I sample the goods? Real fuckin'...
你介意我先? 真插...
Hands off. Stop it. Stop it.
手拿_ 住手 住手
- You're fucking crazy! - Call me.
你他了! - 打我
We got a problem here?
@有什N麻?
- It's all good.
一切都很好 - 一切都很好
It's all good. Just got a little drunk at the bar.
只是在酒吧有c喝大了
Sorry about that.
抱歉
How the fuck have you managed to stay out of prison for a year?
你他出z後 究竟怎N活^一年的
It's been difficult.
一言yM
Like to pay this out in cash or check?
QF金是支票?
Get some Debbie money.
留cF金交o黛比
Four in cash, rest in check.
四成F金 其N支票
Who would you like the check made out to?
您希望用哪家y行的支票?
Texas Midlands Bank.
德州米德my行
Thank you much.
非常xx
Let's go get a room.
我去找房g住下吧
Welcome to the Comanche 66. Do you have a reservation?
g迎入住科曼奇66酒店 有As?
We do not.
]有
Good Lord, look at you.
天 看看你啊
We would be obliged if you would provide accommodations,
如能提供住宿 涌泉相
though we failed to call ahead.
管我]有As
Boy, you are trouble.
你有麻┝
I'm the worst kind, darling.
是最糟糕的那N H鄣
In your last days in the nursing home, you'll think of me and giggle.
在你B院生命的留之H 你想起我 傻傻的笑
Why, God? Why won't you answer my prayers?
槭颤N上帝? 你槭颤N不回我的祈\?
You begged him for help,
你祈求他的椭
and yet you look around at your life and nothing is different.
回首生活 slF一o改
And so you assume that God has told you no.
你告戒自己 是上帝指定的@一切
God doesn't say no.
然而上帝K]有f不
Why couldn't we drive back to Lubbock?
槭颤N我不能_回R博克市?
'Cause they ain't robbing banks in Lubbock.
他不在R博克市劫y行
We're not gonna watch this, are we?
我不能光看不行 Π?
Ain't you Christian?
你不是基督教徒?
Yeah, but I ain't stupid.
我是 但我不蠢
God doesn't talk through this man any more than he talks through my dog.
上帝c@男人的υ K不比上帝c我的狗更多
Well, then maybe you should give your dog a listen.
那你好好A你的狗狗
Ain't you Indian?
你不是印第安人?
You're supposed to be burning sage
你不是身冒火的}人...
and dancing around the bed, whooping like a bee stung you.
著床舞蹈 l出像s蜜蜂一拥穆音
I'm Catholic.
我是天主教徒
Come on.
得了吧
Come on, I'd rather dance around the fire with a spear.
得了 我可e著L矛 著火堆跳舞
I'd rather have you stab me with a spear than watch this.
你看@目不如用L矛捅我算了
This son of a bitch, he wouldn't know God
@王八蛋他不懂上帝
if he crawled up his pant leg and bit him on the pecker.
除非他能云鹧腿 咬自己的老二
Change the damn channel.
他的Q台
Now, this, this is what God watches right here.
F在@才是上帝正在看的
Don't worry, they're gonna have soccer highlights on soon enough.
e心 一就放足球集\
That's for your Mexican half.
因槟阌幸话氲哪西哥血y
Wow, look at this boy run.
哇哦 看@孩子
Longhorns are gonna have a good team this year.
L角牛今年的伍不e啊
That soccer, never could understand that.
足球@N\诱娌荒芾斫
Anything a 5-year-old can do ain't a sport.
五q小屁孩能做到的\硬荒芩氵\
Who invented it? Aztecs?
ll明的 阿芝特克人?
Kickin' around skulls or something, right?
把骷t^之的踢硖呷 是吧?
Sounds like a Comanche sport.
起砀像科曼奇人的\
You know, in three weeks,
知道 三Y拜以後
you can watch whatever you want on TV all day.
你就能整天目S便看了
Hell, you can do it right now in your own room.
或者F在你也可以去你自己房gS便看
Oh, where's the fun in that?
哦 那有什N纷?
You know what, Alberto?
知道 阿托?
What?
怎N?
In a year's time,
用不了一年
it's my teasing that you're gonna miss.
你就想念我的各N玩笑了
It's what you'll laugh about
你o我上、候我的r候...
when you stand over my grave and wish me well.
就X得我的玩笑好笑了
God, I hope that's tomorrow.
老天 我真希望那就是明天啊
Oh, that was a good one.
哦 @玩笑M分
You'll get the hang of this yet.
慢慢你也熟悉玩笑的[T
Isn't it getting late for you?
天色不早了吧?
Yeah.
是啊
Yeah, it is.
是不早了
Oh, heavens above.
噢 老天 老天在上 (前台妹在上)
Heavens above.
天堂在上
Look at those titties. Are you fucking kidding me?
看看@δ套 你他在逗我?
What are you doing?
质颤N呢?
Sleeping on the porch, practicing my future.
睡在T廊 我的未
It's a dangerous thing we do for a living.
我@行很危U
You're lucky...
你很走\...
having seen it through to the end.
已看穿tm
I hope I'm that lucky.
我也希望能有那N幸\
Oh, well.
哦 其
Without me by your side, I doubt you'll get close enough
]有我跟你搭n 恐怕你距x罪犯太近...
to a criminal to ever be in danger again.
早就U境p身了
Just when I was starting to feel sorry for you.
我才想δ惚歉呢
Indians ain't supposed to feel sorry for cowboys.
印第安人才不εＷ斜歉
It's the other way around.
反^聿
And this makes you the executor?
你@算z绦腥?
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼
So, no matter what they charge us with, they can't take it away?
不管他怎N起V我 都o法Z走是?
There's no way to trace funds from a casino, all right?
龅馁Y金o法追吧?
Once you get the checks to the bank, trust is untouchable.
你一旦把支票交oy行  信是o形的
You can't tell nobody nothing, right?
你跟l都不f一字是吧?
Well, what is there to tell?
有什N好f的呢?
I mean, you boys won that money gambling, didn't you?
我的意思是@X你z是博A淼 是吧?
$32,000 pays off the reverse mortgage.
32000美元 付清倒按揭借款
And those bastards paid the property tax from 2012 to now.
那些畜生2012年至今都在抽a
That's another $11,000.
~外的11000美元
So, $43,000 and you are free and clear.
一共43000美元 就汕辶
Just have the loan officer fax me a release of lien,
只要再信JTo我髡嬉留置嘟獬C明
and I'll get that over to the lease manager at Chevron.
我再D交雪佛的租U管理人
- The fax number is on the card. - Okay.
髡嫣a在@名片上 - 好的
How much you making on this deal?
你诌@文甓嗌馘X?
Not near as much as I'm risking.
甑牟蛭颐暗娘LU
Why you doin' it, then?
那你槭颤N干?
You know, they loaned the least they could.
你知道 他付o你的借款能少t少
Just enough to keep your mama poor on a guaranteed return.
只蜃你老F的有基本承Z收益
Thought they could swipe her land for $25,000.
最後只用了25000刀I走她的地皮
That's just so arrogant, it makes my teeth hurt.
太狂了 恨得我牙WW
To see you boys...
看到你z…
pay those bastards back with their own money?
用那托笊自己的Xo自己?
Well, if that ain't Texan, I don't know what is.
如果@不是德州人作L 我都不知道什N是了
Thank you.
多x了
Now, they can foreclose on Friday.
他星期五就取K止抵押品的H回
Come hell or high water,
你就算赴蹈火
be at the bank in Childress on Thursday.
也要在星期四s到柴Y德斯的y行
Knowing them fuckers, they will close early.
他那群混蛋提早Y束II的
- We'll be there. - Oh, and, Toby.
及r到_的 - 叫我托比
The trust needs to be managed by a bank.
信必由y行
You really wanna cover your tracks?
你真的想要[藏Y金的流向?
You get Texas Midland to handle this trust.
你得找德州米德m砀氵@信
So, what's the plan?
那N 是?
We're gonna watch that bank like a deer feeder.
盯著那家y行
In time, we'll be right.
rgC明我是Φ
Now, let's see what they got to eat here.
F在我看看都有些什N吃的
Howdy, ma'am. How you doing today?
你好 大姐 今天^的怎N?
Hot, and I don't mean the good kind.
很 不舒服的
So, what don't you want?
好了 你不想要什N?
Pardon?
抱歉?
What don't you want?
你不想要什N?
Oh, well, uh, I think I'll just, uh...
哦 @ 我看我就呃…
You know, I've been working here for 44 years.
知道 我在@干了44年了
Ain't nobody ever ordered nothing
]有人c^...
but T-bone steak and a baked potato.
除了T骨牛排以外的|西
Except this one asshole from New York
除了一位募~s淼亩
tried to order trout back in 1987.
1987年 那r他想c三文~
We don't sell no goddamned trout.
我家聿毁u特奶奶的三文~
T-bone steaks.
只uT骨牛排
So, either you don't want the corn on the cob,
但你可以不要玉米棒子
or you don't want the green beans.
要N不要青豆
So, what don't you want?
所以 你不要什N?
I don't want green beans.
我不要青豆
I don't want green beans either.
我也不要青豆
Steaks cooked medium rare.
牛排三分熟
- Can I get my steak cooked... - That weren't no question.
我的牛排可以的... - 不S多嘴
All right.
好吧
Iced tea for you boys.
o你冰茶
Iced tea would be great.
冰茶不e
Iced tea, yep. Thank you, ma'am.
冰茶 xx 大姐
Uh-huh.
嗯哼
Well, I'll tell you one thing.
好吧 我告V你件事
Nobody's gonna rob this son of a bitch.
]人劫@老太婆
My word.
相信我
How's she feel?
感X她怎N?
She runs good.
跑的不e
Ain't gonna win any races.
但A不了什N比吧
Got New Mexico plates.
A^新墨西哥碟
She got a top?
她A^冠?
How she came.
到底怎N
We'll take her.
我要她了
Don't report it stolen till Friday.
星期五 再蟾媸Ц`
The guy from Chevron is dropping off the lease agreement.
雪佛的那夥又p少了租Ufhl款
Are you okay dealing with that by yourself?
你自理]}吧?
You okay being with Debbie
一人去黛比那Y行?
Remember, he ain't the enemy.
住他可不是橙
Just take the papers, say thank you.
拿上文件走人 要fxx
The oil man is the enemy, make no mistake.
那油商才是橙 e犯e
He just ain't ours.
他不是我的目
I'll be back to the ranch by dark.
我天黑前就回r
I will be waiting.
我等你
Drive like a schoolteacher with all this shit in the back.
_得像模教 竟後面b了一大堆玩意
Sure feels like beer o'clock.
到啤酒rg了吧
Ask and you shall receive.
只管_口
Come in.
M
Mama died.
死了
When?
什Nr候
A few weeks ago.
Y拜前
Well, good riddance.
好吧 K於[了
No offense.
o意冒犯
You Okay?
你好?
You?
你呢?
Here's the money I owe you.
@是我欠你的X
I guess you'll be selling the ranch.
我以槟u掉牧
It goes to the boys.
它是孩子的了
- Really? - Mmm.
是 - 嗯
It's been put in a trust.
它算M信里了
What's that mean?
什N意思?
It means no one can sell it.
就是f]有人能u掉它
Great.
@下好了
Something else I got to take care of.
我又有新|西得照看了
Hi.
嗨
Where's your brother?
你弟弟呢?
I don't know.
我不知道
Friend's house, I guess.
也S在朋友家Y吧
How come you ain't in school?
你怎N不上W?
School don't start yet.
]_W
Just two-a-days for football right now.
F在就是一天纱伍烨
Your grandmother died.
你奶奶去世了
I'm giving the ranch to you and your brother.
我把牧鼋唤o你和你弟弟
Remember going out there when you was little?
得你小r候去^那Y?
What am I supposed to do with a ranch?
我要拿那牧鲈觞Nk?
Anything but sell it.
怎佣夹 就是不能u
We found oil on it.
Y面有石油
You and your brother ain't gonna have to worry about money no more.
你和你弟弟拇o需殄X
Now...
F在_始...
you may be hearing a lot of things about me and...
你到很多有P我和...
your uncle.
和你叔叔之g的事
Don't be like us.
不要W我
You hear me?
明白?
Whatever I hear, I won't believe.
不管我f了什N 我都不相信的
No, you believe it.
不 你得相信
I did all of it.
一切全是我做的
Now, you, you do it different.
你要走不同的人生之路
Ain't gonna drink it?
不打算喝?
You tell me not to be like you, and then you offer me a beer.
你我不要像你一 so我啤酒
Which is it?
到底要怎?
Good boy.
好孩子
- How are the boys? - What are you doin'?
孩子好? - 你在质颤N?
Insurance.
做些保U措施
I don't want that shit in the car.
我不想上那破玩意
We'll be running two cars next time, brother.
老兄 我下次_奢v
They'll ride with me.
我上它
So, this is your plan?
所以 @就是你的?
We're just gonna sit here
我就@幼在@Y
and see if this is the branch they rob next.
z@家分行是不是被他劫
What would you rather do?
那你又怎幼?
You wanna drive 80 miles back to Olney
你意80英里去W尼...
and look for more fingerprints that we ain't gonna find?
找那些根本就]有影的指y?
Or you wanna drive 200 miles back to Lubbock
是你想_200英里回R博克市
and look at mugshots that don't matter 'cause nobody knows
去看那些oPo要的部照片 因焊就]有人...
what these sons of bitches look like?
知道@些王八蛋L什N?
Or we can just wait here for them to rob this bank,
不然 我就在@等著他@家y行
which is the one thing I'm pretty damn sure they are going to do.
而我又十分_定他一定淼
I know what you're doing.
我知道你想致
You're trying to make this last as long as you can
你在M力拖延rg
because the longer it lasts,
拖得rg越L
the farther you are from that front porch.
你xT廊想的未砭驮竭h
No, I'm waitin' for these boys to make a mistake.
]有 我在等@些砘锓稿e
So far they ain't, but they will.
目前]有 但他肯定出岔子
And they're gonna make it here.
而且就在@家y行
So, just relax.
所以 放p
Enjoy this little town.
好好享受小的生活吧
Do you wanna live here?
你想住在@Y?
Got an old hardware store
只有一家古老的五金店
that charges twice what Home Depot does,
物品售r是家得（美家居Bi店）的杀
one restaurant with a rattlesnake for a waitress.
有一家餐^ 女招待的皮w堪比尾蛇(的尾h)
I mean, how is anybody supposed to make a living here?
我是f @Y的人都怎N生活?
People have made a living here for 150 years.
@Y住人有150年v史
Well, people lived in caves for 150,000 years,
那人在洞穴Y住了十五f年呢
but they don't do it no more.
但你F在不住山洞了啊
Well, maybe your people did.
也S你的族人@幼
Your people did, too.
你那拥娜艘
A long time ago, your ancestors was the Indians...
很久之前 你的祖先是印第安人...
till someone came along and killed them,
直到另外有人硗⑺
broke 'em down, made you into one of them.
把他sM⒔^ 把你同化
150 years ago, all this was my ancestors' land.
150年前 @Y全都是我祖先的土地
Everything you can see.
你F在所看到的一切
Everything you saw yesterday.
以及你昨天看到的一切
Till the grandparents of these folks took it.
你的祖Z走了一切
And now, it's been taken from them.
F在 到他被Z取了
Except it ain't no army doing it.
^e是 不再佑梦淞
It's those sons of bitches right there.
就是那Y的王八蛋(y行家)干的
You thinking about tomorrow?
你在想明天的事?
Ain't you?
你]想?
The little hotel clerk.
那小酒店的前台妹
Why is it always the sweet ones
槭颤N那些看起硖鹈赖娜
that are such devils when you get them revved up?
一旦狂暴起 得那N狂放?
Wouldn't know. Never had a sweet one.
不知道 ]遇甜美型的
Yeah, you like them pissed off, lookin' for someone to blame.
你喜g他狂放 似乎在找人
Sure seems that way.
的_是那影
It's a good thing you're doing.
你做的很不e
We're doing it.
是我z做的
Go easy on the bank teller tomorrow.
明天y行出{T好c
I'll be as gentle as a young nurse.
我像年po士那拥厝
You coming?
你?
On my Way-
R上
Hey.
嘿
Shit.
死
Morning.
早上好
You want some breakfast?
你想要早餐?
Yeah, breakfast sounds good.
好啊 起聿诲e
So we hit the Jayton branch first, then Coleman, right?
我先去茴D分行 再去科曼分行 ?
Yeah, that should get us what we need.
好的 @差不多盗
Let's do this.
邮职
Ugh... shit.
的 死
That's not part of the fucking plan.
可他的不是@
The bastards closed down the branch.
那群混蛋把@家分行oP了
What now, little brother?
F在怎Nk 老弟?
Coleman.
去科曼分行
- What the hell you doing? - We gotta head to Post.
你他的在质颤N? - 我得去一趟]局
- What the hell are you doing? - Get...
你他的在质颤N - 得去...
- We got to head to Post. - What are you talking about?
我得去一趟]局 - 你在f什N?
We got to head to Post.
我必去一趟]局
We're going to Coleman.
我先去科曼
There's only one teller in Coleman.
科曼只有一名出{
Whatever we get won't be enough.
o如何都是不殿~的
We go to Coleman right now.
我F在就得去科曼
If that ain't enough, we head to Post.
如果那Y不虻脑就去]局
If we don't leave now for Post, we won't get there till noon.
如果F在不去]局 那就得中午才能到
You don't wanna rob a bank at lunchtime, do you?
你可不想午rgy行吧?
Yeah, we don't know the patterns of folks out there.
我又不知道那地人的T
The patterns are the same everywhere.
@NT 都是一拥
All these towns are dead. Post ain't no different.
@些城都僵化了 ]局也是一
It's a bigger bank.
那可是家大y行
We'll leave your car just out of town.
我得把你的留在城外
Come on, now.
快c吧
Shit.
操
I think I got this figured.
我想我弄懂了
First two banks, they were Texas Midland Banks.
前杉毅y行 都是德州米德my行
All right, there are seven branches altogether.
好了 米德my行一共有七家分行
The main branch is in Fort Worth.
行在沃思堡市
They're not gonna mess with that.
他是不去那Y的
All right, they hit the branch in Olney.
他去了W尼分行
They hit the one in Archer City.
去了阿爻堑哪羌
- Then there's the one here. - Which they did not hit.
@Y有一家 - 他未劫
Alberto, will you please follow me?
阿托 你可以跟著我的思路?
Don't let... just keep your mouth shut
]上嘴 e多
and just listen to what I'm gonna say.
好好著 我要f什N
There's the one here...
@有一家...
then there's the one in Childress.
柴德Y斯有一家
There's the one in Jayton.
茴D有一家
That one's closed.
@家PT了
I know that one's closed!
我知道@家PT了!
I know that one's closed, Alberto.
我知道@家PT了 阿托
That's my point.
我想f的是...
Jayton is closed.
茴D那家PT了
That just leaves Post.
就只剩]局了
They're not gonna mess with the bank in Childress.
他不去搞柴德Y斯的分行
That's a fairly decent-sized town.
那子l展很不e
The branch in Vernon wasn't Midlands and they hit that.
弗r那家不是米德m的 也被他劫了
Yeah, one of them did. Alone.
他其中一去的 就一人
Then he ran all the way across the road to get to the car.
他一直跑^R路 去那
I think his partner had no idea that was gonna happen.
他的同夥@然都]有料到l生@件事
What does that mean to us?
@ξ有什Nr值呢?
It means that the only branch that fits the bill is in Post.
@f明他唯一去的地方就是]局
Well, then let's go.
那好吧 咱去吧
The town looks busy.
@地方看起砗芊泵
Little bit.
有一c
My word.
相信我
It's too big.
@家太大了
That's what she said.
@她f的
It's no good.
@很不妙
Aw, this ain't your first rodeo.
哎 @又不是你的首秀了
Bigger bank...
y行越大
more money.
X越多
Everybody, get on the fucking ground!
所有人 都他趴到地上!
Get on the fucking ground!
他的趴在地上!
Young ladies, get on the fucking ground! Now!
小姐 他的趴在地上 F在!
Sir, down! On the ground! Now!
先生 趴下 趴在地上! 快!
Thank you very much.
非常感x你
Tellers, stand up!
出{T 全w起立!
Open the drawers!
把抽洗蜷_!
Get down!
趴好了!
Take three steps back!
o我向後三步!
Open the fucking drawer, young lady!
都他把抽辖o我打_ 女士!
Are you deaf and dumb?
你是@是蠢?
I said open the motherfucking drawer!
我f你他快o我打_抽!
- You, down! - All right. Oh, please.
你趴好了! - 好了 快
Now step back!
F在向後退!
Someone's paying attention.
都o我好了
Now get on your motherfucking knees!
F在 都他的o我跪下!
Hey!
嘿
Stay down!
趴下!
All right.
好了
Dude.
兄弟
Hey, hey, let's go!
嘿嘿 快走!
Call 911!
快打911
Jesus fucking Christ.
真他日了狗啊
The whole goddamn town is shooting at us.
全人都他在朝我_
Get in the back. Get in the fucking back.
去後 去他的後箱
Come on, let's go! Get in the car!
快c 上追!
Don't let them get away!
e他跑了!
How you doing back there, little brother?
你在後面好 弟弟?
You fucking killed them.
你他的竟然⑷肆
These concealed carry permits
那些偷偷е砘锏娜...
sure complicate a bank robbery, don't they?
@然也是劫匪吧?
It's not my fault it was payday.
不是我的e 鬼知道今天是l薪日
This has gone too far, Tan.
@次太出格了 阿坦
No one was supposed to fucking die.
本聿有人死的
It was them or us. Take your pick.
不是他死就是我亡 自己x
Yeah, go, Margaret.
是的 f吧 格特
Texas Midlands in Post has just been hit.
德州米m德]局遭遇劫
Ah! What did I tell you?
我f什N碇?
Yeah.
好
- Yeah! - Locals are in chase.
嗯  - 地的警察正在追捕他
Suspects escaping west
嫌犯{著一v...
in an old Bronco.
破f的野R向西逃去
All right, Margaret, keep us posted. We're on our way there.
明白了 格特 保持j 我正s^去
Give me an Indian whoop. Come on.
o我一印第安式的嚎叫 戆
These boys are gonna go down.
那些小子要吃T了
Let's get some giddy-up music going on there.
睃chh然的音
Oh, please, not that.
不要@曲
Yeah.
耶
Hey, hey. Come on. Snap out of it.
嘿 so^
Snap the fuck out of it.
快他o我^
Shit, let me see that. You're hit.
的 o我看看 你中了
Boy, you're hit. Get the back.
孩子 你被打中了 D^去
Well, you'll live. It's a through and through.
你活下淼 百分百]}
Compress it. Wrap it up. You got to wrap it up tight.
壕o口 然後包好 必oo包住
Front and back, front and back.
前後都要包 前後
Wrap it tight.
包oc
Oh, brother, hear me now, hear me clear.
噢 兄弟 F在o我J真好了
Unless you wanna be a black mark on your sons' lives,
如果你不想成槟愫⒆由命中的污c
I need you mountain lion mean.
拿出c美洲{精神
You hear me?
到了?
I hear you.
到了
- Mountain lion mean. - Yeah.
美洲{精神 -
Yeah. It's gonna be okay. It's gonna be okay.
]事的 一切都好的
- Hold on. - Yeah.
猿肿
Go.
快走
Here, take the money.
o 把X拿著
- Let's go. - Get to the casino.
咱走 - 去瞿
Change the money like we planned.
按洗X
This was your plan, and it worked.
@是你的 @_有效
Every step of the way.
每一步都是
Trust it.
相信自己
Where are you headed?
你淙ツ?
Don't be stupid.
e傻了
I love you, Toby.
我勰 托比
I mean it.
我J真的
I love you, too.
我也勰
Hey, Tobe, go fuck yourself.
嘿 托比 去你的
Go fuck yourself.
去你的
As I walked out one sunny morning
*光N的早晨我信步而行*
I spied a young cowboy a loping along
*一眼瞅牛仔哥~著大步*
His hat was laid back
*他的帽子煸诒翅*
His spurs were a jinglin'
*他的R刺叮叮的*
And as he come near me He's singing this song
*他走近我的r候 唱著@首歌*
Yippee hiyiyo. You little doggies.
*咿辟咳咿吼 你@小狗狗*
It's your misfortune and none of my own
*@是你的不幸 而不是我的*
This is what they call white man's intuition.
@就是所^白人的直X
Sometimes a blind pig finds a truffle.
也叫瞎抓到死老鼠
It's your misfortune and none of my own
*@是你的不幸 而不是我的*
Back up! Oh, shit!
快後退 噢 靠!
Go! Move!
快 快 快走!
My word.
相信我
All right, We're gonna need a SWAT unit up here
好吧 看砦需要一支特警
and a helo to pin these boys down.
和一架直升wC 碜ツ砘锪
Suspect is a white male.
嫌犯是一名白人男性
Guys, spread it out!
所有人散_
He's got a rifle. Get down!
Ψ匠钟械 腰!
Come on, I see him!
我看他了!
There's just one?
只有一人?
Yep, just one.
是的 只有一人
There's supposed to be two of them.
本硎怯人的
Maybe the town folks got one.
也S在上就抓住了一
Well, if they did, they got the smart one.
那N抓住的那 肯定是明出主意的人
This old boy is out of his mind.
@老小子直了
Why don't you slip up this canyon and tomahawk that son of a bitch?
你不如翻越{谷 用斧u@混蛋?
Ranger down. Call it in.
巡警奚 求支援
Get back! Back! Back those trucks up!
快倒 後退 @些皮卡都後退!
Get back!
後退!
Get these trucks back.
那些卡都後退
Back up!
快後退!
Back them up.
他後退
How well do you know the land around here?
你熟悉@的地形?
Like the back of my hand.
t如指掌
All right, he's hid up in that brush on that hill.
那好 他就藏在那山脊惭Y
Can you get me up there behind him?
能我@到他後面去?
Give me a half hour, I'll have that bastard
o我30分 可以拿下那混蛋
field dressed on the hood of my truck.
後面的地形正好能o我的做掩o
I can't let you do that. You just get me there.
你]必要@N做 只管我^去
That's gonna be a 500-yard shot if he's where you said.
如果真像你f的那 那可足足500ah
Just get me there!
只管我^去!
Shit.
操
How are you doing?
你好?
Good. You?
好 你呢?
Where are you headed?
你淙ツ耗?
Ruidoso.
伊多索
Where you from?
你哪淼?
Hamlin.
哈姆林
Taking the scenic route?
x@N荒龅穆肪?
Taking the only way I can.
x了l唯一能走的路而已
They got the road closed at Post.
他封了]局的路
Everywhere you turn they got the road closed.
每一l下口都被封了
- You got your license on you? - Yes, I do.
я{照了? - 是的 我Я
Wait right there.
在@稍等一下
Yes, sir.
好的 L官
- Sir. - Yeah.
先生 - 嗯
Have a good day.
一路L
Thanks much.
多x
You're pretty winded.
你有c喘不上獍
You oughta let me take the shot. Hell, it's my gun.
你我黹_ 鬼了 @可是我的
Not on your life.
F在不是了
He's mine.
他是我的
Just left of the tree.
就在涞淖筮
I got him.
我砀愣ㄋ
I got you.
我看到你了
Lord of the Plains.
平原之王
That's me.
就是我
Texas Highway Patrol and the locals
德州高速路巡和地警察
chased the robbers to this hillside behind me,
在我身後的山上追s匪
20 miles west of town, where the gunfight continued.
子西的20里外 交火依然在^m
And right now we do know
F在我得知
Ranger Marcus Hamilton killed one of the gunmen
巡警察R焖埂h密D借用地居民的一把砀
using a rifle he actually borrowed from a resident here.
懒似渲幸持嫌犯
We don't know the name of that suspect yet...
我F在不清楚@嫌犯的名字
Lucky guy-
真走\
Just in the nick of time, too.
rg卡得好
What are the odds?
@N概率不太有
Now, this, uh, satisfies
好吧 F在@PX
both the reverse mortgage loan and the, uh...
正好能清倒按揭借款和...
and the back taxes that we've paid on your mother's behalf.
我替你母H代付的款
We do that as courtesy, of course.
然 我@N做是出於好心
You can fax the release of lien to that number.
把留置嘟獬C明髡娼o@a
An attorney?
一律?
All right, well, I'll... I'll get that faxed over to your attorney
好的 嗯 我把|西髡姘l^去...
by the end of the week.
在@L末之前
It is the end of the week. I wanna watch you do it.
F在就是L末 我要H眼看著你做
Well, it takes a little time to prepare.
@需要crg
I got all day.
我一天都有空
Here we go.
有了
Okay. That's it.
好的 就@
And it's been a pleasure doing business with you.
很s幸c你接洽
Let me ask you a question.
你}
Do y'all manage trusts?
你有信I?
Hey, Marcus, ain't you supposed to be retired?
嘿 R焖 你不是退休了?
Howdy.
你好
- Shelley. - Nice to see you.
雪莉 - 很高d看你
- Well, hey, Marcus. - Hey, Margaret.
你好 R焖 - 嘿 格特
Been awhile. How's life as a civilian?
一子老百姓的滋味怎N?
Oh, just, you know...
就 你知道的...
Think I can take a peek at Mr. Howard's file?
我可以看一下霍A德的n案?
Tanner Howard.
坦{・霍A德
Oh, come on. I ain't got nothing better to do.
行了 我]有更好的差事可
It's at my desk.
在我的桌子上
Uh...
呃
Killed his father in a hunting accident, huh?
他在一次狩C事故中 ⒘怂父H是吧?
I'd love to know what he was hunting in the barn in April.
我倒是想知道四月份的Y}里 有什N可以狩C的
10 years in Huntsville for aggravated assault.
因乐害罪 被P押在亨茨S十年
Cellmate was released in 2012.
他的z友於2012年被放
Before that, he served seven years
@刑7年 他因劫大斯普林市y行...
on bank robbery charges up in Big Spring.
被提起公V
Been trying to track him down, but no luck so far.
一直D追捕其z友 但至今仍是未果
You all are off the brother?
你都忽略了他的兄弟?
There's nothing that links him to the robberies.
他和@些劫案毫oPS
Now, what about that little waitress in Vernon?
那弗r市的小服T又怎N解?
Yeah, we showed her photos.
我o她看了照片
She said she didn't recognize him.
她f不JR他
Pretty upset you took her tips as evidence.
而且你拿走她的小M 令她O其沮
She sure was sassy.
她^υ诟闶
You show that to that old timer?
你把照片o那位老油子看了?
Yep. He said he didn't look like the fella from the diner.
看了 他f他不像是那用餐的小伙
He didn't recognize Tanner's photo either.
他也]J出坦{
Yeah, tried to get a court order on his bank accounts and the ranch,
想法庭判令{查他的y行~艉娃r
DA wouldn't do it.
地z官才不做@事
Toby's got no record. He's never been arrested.
托比案底清白 ]有任何犯罪
His only court appearance was at his divorce.
唯一出庭是x婚案
He don't fit the bill, Marcus.
他K不符合案情 R焖
People don't start out robbing banks.
人不是一出生就劫的
They graduate to it like his asshole brother.
是要慢慢升的 比如他的混蛋哥哥
Besides, when we was out there,
再f 我到那的r候
we saw two crews from Chevron
看山M雪佛的T工
capping wells and putting in pumpjacks.
一Mw井帽 一M安b石油井
Engineers out there said they're gonna pull
F龉こf@Y...
2,000 barrels a month off that place.
每月a出2000桶原油
You just try convincing a judge to issue warrants on somebody
你X得法官o你授...
set to clear $50,000 a month
以劫管理信的y行四f美元槊立案
for robbing $40,000 from the bank that manages the family trust.
而那人s每月Q入5f美元
Midland manages the trust?
米德m管理信I?
You'd think they'd want this thing figured out.
你J殂y行是想查水落石出
I don't think the bank cares about anything
我X得y行什N都不在乎
but keeping that trust right where it is.
除了S持信的正常\行
Hell, they were less cooperative than Toby's attorney.
死 y行方面比托比的律不肯配合
Marcus, he's not a suspect and you are retired.
R焖 他不是嫌疑犯 你也已退休了
Oh, I hear you.
哦 你的
You like my desk?
你喜g@桌子?
I don't hate it.
至少不
Hey, I'll see you, Marcus.
嘿 回^ R焖
Know who I am?
知道我是l?
I'm the man who killed your brother.
我是⒘四愀绺绲娜
I know.
我知道
I also know you're retired and you're trespassing.
我知道你已退休 你@算擅J
Well, you could shoot me now and be within your rights.
哦 你F在就可以懒宋 你的嗬
You toting a gun and all, how convenient.
你手扣在扳C上 多方便
I figure you got one, too.
我猜你也有一支
Mind if I sit?
介意我坐?
Go ahead.
M戆
You want a beer?
啤酒?
Sure. I ain't on duty no more.
可以 我再也不用糖诹
Thanks.
x了
It's nice out here in this breeze, huh,
在@坐著吹著小L真芤
now that it's cooled down.
管F在已降亓
How did you do it?
你怎N做到的?
Oh, never mind.
算我]f
I'll figure that out in time.
哦 ]PS 我及r搞清楚的
Why? Why did you do it?
槭颤N?槭颤N要帜鞘?
I know why your brother, Tanner, did it.
我可以理解你哥哥坦{的C
He robbed them banks because he liked it.
他y行是因樗喜g
He shot my partner 300 yards away 'cause he liked it.
他在300a外射死了我的同事 就因樗喜g
It made him feel good.
...X得爽
If I hadn't blown his shit for brains out,
如果不是我一射爆他的X{
there'd be a new truck out front with jet skis
@T口有另外一v湫碌钠た K外焖上摩托
or whatever else he could think to buy.
或者他想I啥就I啥
He'd spend it all just to give an excuse to steal some more.
他花光所有X 好o他藉口再去偷
But not you.
但你不@
There's nothing new around here...
]o@YI什N新|西...
except them pumpjacks.
除了井
Each one of them making you a month
@些C器砘锩月...
what you and your brother stole from all four banks combined.
o你的X大大超^你兄弟zB四家y行的和
Help me understand, then.
那N臀蚁胂
Help me understand why four people died...
臀蚁朊靼锥加兴人G了性命...
so you could steal money that it don't seem you've spent,
似乎你淼腻X K]有花掉
that it don't seem you need.
感X@XK不是急需的
You got a family?
你有家人?
My partner had a family. A big one.
我搭n 一大家子人
They don't got no pumpjacks in their backyard.
他家後院可]有石油井
- I didn't kill your friend. - Yes, you did.
我]⒛愕呐笥 - 不 你⒘
By setting this thing in motion.
你幕後策的一切
You expect me to believe your dimwitted brother planned this?
你X得我相信是你X抽的哥哥策的一切?
Oh, no. This was smart.
才不 策很明
This was you.
明的是你
I've been poor my whole life.
我F了一子
So were my parents, their parents before them.
我父母F 祖父母也F
It's like a disease...
F就像z鞑...
passing from generation to generation, becomes a sickness.
一代又一代地飨氯 成B疾
That's what it is.
就是@
Infects every person you know...
魅窘o你JR的每一人...
but not my boys.
但我鹤硬荒茉俑F下去了
Not anymore.
不可以
This is theirs now.
F在@凫端
Now, I ain't never killed no one in my life,
我一生]⑦^人
but if you want me to start with you, let's get on with it, old man.
但如果你想我哪汩_刀 老人家
See if you can grab that pistol before I blast you off this porch.
看看你抽出手之前 我能否一Z翻你
- Howdy. - What's going on?
你好 - 怎N回事?
The hogs are back in the garden.
家i回家了啊
Feral hogs tearing up this place something fierce.
野i_道 游疵
Who's this?
@是哪位?
I'm an old friend of your husband.
我是你丈夫的一老朋友
Ex-husband.
是前夫
I'm just working on the house.
我只是硌b修房子的
Oh, you don't live here?
哦 你不住在@Y?
No, it's not mine. It's theirs.
不 @Y不凫段 是他的房a
Oh.
哦
The things we do for our kids, huh?
造福後代的事情
Well...
那N
I best be going.
我最好走了
Ma'am.
女士
Me, too, Debbie. I'm gonna wash up,
我也走了 黛比 我要去洗洗乾Q
be back around 9:00 tomorrow to finish the front.
大概明天9c回硗瓿汕伴T的活
Start painting the extension
然後浞鬯⑵漯N部分
and then help Randy with his homework
等m迪放W回家後
when he gets back from school, okay?
和他完成作I 好?
Okay-
好的
Hey.
嘿
I rent a little house in town.
我在上租了一g小屋
If you wanna stop by and finish this conversation,
如果你想找我^m@
you're welcome anytime.
Srg迎
Oh, I'd like that.
哦 我的
I'll be seeing you.
回^了
Yeah. Soon, I hope.
是啊 很快 我想
I'm ready to be done with this.
我浜昧私Y@一切了
You'll never be done with it no matter what.
你永h都不了Y o是什N
It's gonna haunt you, son, for the rest of your days.
它伴S你K身 孩子
But you won't be alone.
但你不孤
It's gonna haunt me, too.
它也伴S我K身
If you stop by, maybe I'll give you peace.
如你有空拜L 也S我o你安
Maybe. Maybe I'll give it to you.
也S吧 也S是我o你安